本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流
パルス暦３２０年１２月
The era of Parsis, December 320 years.
更多中日双语字幕，尽在www.kamigami.org 及微博@诸神字幕组
Arslan reached Peshavarda, the fortress on the border,
国境の城塞　ペシャワールに入城を果たしたアルスラーンの前に
where a man in a silver mask,
突如　銀仮面の男　ヒルメスが襲いかかった
Hermes, she attacked him.
殿下
Prince!
If you kill him,
あの方を殺せば　パルス王家の正統な血が絶えてしまう
legal race royal family Parsis interrupted it.
ヒルメスの凶刃からアルスラーンを守った老将バフマン
The sword of Hermes Arslan rescued General Bachmann.
だが　彼の今際の言葉はアルスラーンの心に大きな影を落とした
But his last words were discouraged Arslan.
そんななか　東方の大国　シンドゥラ侵攻の急報が伝えられた
And in the midst of all this was reported,
sindoor approaching army, the powerful eastern kingdom.
ガーデーヴィめに先を越されてなるものか
I will not let this pass me Gadevi.
シンドゥラ国の歴史に不滅の名を刻むのは
In sindoor history will forever be engraved one name ...
この俺よ
My!
kaze ga zawameki kudaketa kimochi
Quiet wind awakens emotions and broken,
日听&翻译
小伍
sora
兰樱
校对
小江
mam
misukashi teru you de furueta yo
I see through everything and I shiver.
michita tsuki no hi touboe no inochi
In the sky a full moon, and the city comes howling:
片源
Rei
时间轴
钦钦&框框
压制
久嘉
Coolkid
mada oite kanaide yo
"Please do not throw until we have!"
bokura torikaeseru ka na iro tsuki no sora
Will we return to the old sky, painted in the colors?
hokori mamire no yume mai agete
Rise in the dance vortex hourglass Sci,
kobushi wo nigittanara
to be clamped in their fists.
ima hashire hashire tsuji kaze ni natte
Now run forward, run forward, and stand by the whirlwind,
rettou zetsubou issai fukitobashite iku
feelings of hopelessness and despair of sour cream on the way.
oikakenakya saigo no tobira
Clears the currently last track.
nando chittatte dai gyakuten
Let all break, we will rise again,
kono goe ga shagare tatte inorinouta todoketai yo
even a hoarse voice will sing songs and prayers.
tarinai bokura de shinji teta sekai wo ubaetara
Even insignificant, as we will be able to capture the whole world in which to believe.
madamada madamada make rarenai
We have still not yet been defeated!
Chapter XIV
fortress Peshawar
侵攻してきたシンドゥラ軍の数は　ざっと見積もって５万
The army has invaded sindoor
nearly fifty thousand people.
すでに国境の川を越え　パルス領内に入っています
They had already crossed the river on the border
and set foot on the land Parsis.
まったく…　次から次へと厄介事ばかり降りかかってくるものだ
Yeah, hour by hour is not easier.
Troubles continue to accompany us.
殿下
Prince.
ああ　すまない
Sorry.
ご気分がすぐれぬようでしたら　一度お休みください
If you feel unwell, better rest.
We can handle here.
ここは我々が…
いや
No.
私なら大丈夫だ
I'm fine.
Please be a good king ...
よい王とおなりくだされ…
皆　聞いてくれ
People listen.
エクバターナへ進軍する前に　まずは降りかかる火の粉を払わねばならぬ
Before we go to Ecbatana,
you need to deal with the emerging problem.
ここでシンドゥラを迎え撃つぞ
We here will repulse sindoor!
The second prince of the kingdom sindoor, Rajendra
おお　冷たい　冷たい
How cool.
なるほど　これが雪というものか
Clear. This is what is called "snow."
ラジェンドラ殿下
Prince Rajendra we should have exactly starting this invasion?
本当に侵攻を開始してしまってよかったのでしょうか
何を言う
What are you?
パルス国内が混乱している今こそ　絶好の機会であろうが
Now the situation is precarious in Pars.
This is a great opportunity.
As to the situation, then this also applies to our kingdom.
混乱というなら　我が国とてそうでありましょう
国王カリカーラ二世陛下がお倒れになった今
Now, when there was our ruler, His Majesty King II of Karikaly,
殿下がシンドゥラを留守にされては…
Prince missing in sindoor ...
ガーデーヴィか
Gadevi, yes?
ヤツのことなら　気にする必要はない
On it there is no need to worry.
何が第一王子だ
What other first prince?
たかが　ひと月ほど早く生まれただけだろう
He was born just a month earlier.
才能も器量も　どう考えても　俺の方が王としてふさわしい
According to their abilities and skills,
no matter what, and the throne is more suitable for me.
殿下
Prince!
さあ　パルスの王太子の首を手土産に　王都に凱旋といこうか
So, how about take the head of the Crown Prince Parsis
as a souvenir on his return to the capital?
殿下
Prince.
殿下　出撃準備が整いました
Prince, we are ready to go into battle.
行ってまいります
We stand.
そうか
Clear.
Drug ...
あの…
何か
What?
私もやはり　出陣した方がよくないか
Perhaps I, too, should go into battle?
What?
はい
私だけ　ただここで座って待っているのでは　申し訳が立たない
If I'm just going to sit here alone and waiting for the break a promise.
私にも何かできることがあるはずだろう
I, too, can do something.
殿下…
Prince.
You are now
今やあなたはこのペシャワールの数万の兵を束ねる身
manages several tens of thousands of people in Peshavarde.
いちいち御自ら戦場に出られる必要はありません
You do not need to go out on the field every time.
But...
だが…
Count this time on us.
今回は我々にお任せください
必ずや吉報をお届けしましょう
We will definitely bring you good news.
分かった　お主たちのやりやすいようにやってくれ
Good.
Do as you would be easier.
まったく　昨日のことを気にされているのかと思えば
Yeah. I yesterday and thought that it is something disturbing.
まあ　それを考えたくもないというのもあろうがな
Well, I'm sure of it, he would not think of.
ただ座っているだけでは皆に申し訳が立たぬ…か
Said, breaking a promise, if it is to just sit and wait, huh?
一軍の将の言葉とは思えんな
I can not believe that this is the word army commander.
本当に心優しいお方だ
He has a very kind soul.
だが　ただ優しいだけでは王にはなれぬ
But a little kindness, to become king.
そうかな
You think?
ああいうお方だからこそ　我々も兵たちも信じてついていける
It is because he is,
we and other people believe in him and follow him.
一人くらいは　そんな王がいてもいいのではないか
Perhaps, at least one can be the king.
Exactly.
確かにな
さあ　行くぞ　殿下に吉報をお届けすると約束したからな
Well, let's go.
After all, we promised to bring good news to Prince.
アルスラーン…
Lions ...
つくづくヤツの行く先には争いが絶えませぬな
At every step, where he steps,
He faced only with strife.
放っておいてよろしいのですかな
We believe that it is necessary to leave it?
ダリューンらが城を離れた今　あの小僧を殺すには絶好の機会かと思われますが
Daryuna and the other in the fortress there,
this is the best opportunity to finally kill the guy.
We go back to Ecbatana.
エクバターナに戻るぞ
いいでしょう
Good.
では　作戦どおり　我々は先に行かせてもらうぞ
So, as planned, we will go forward.
ああ　よろしく頼む
Yes, we count on you.
ナルサス　聞きたいことがある
Narsus, I have a question.
What?
なんだ
侵攻してきたシンドゥラの兵は５万
The army sindoor fifty thousand soldiers.
We also only ten thousand.
対して　こちらは１万の兵しか出していない
Yes.
ああ
少数の兵で多数の兵を破るというのは　邪道ではなかったか
Is not it strange to go less against a large army?
今回はあえて邪道をいくのさ
At this time, we have deliberately resorted to this.
ダリューン　お前はかつてセリカで
Daryun you once in Serik
recognized three principles on which it is worth remembering the war,
戦いにあたって注意すべき三つの理とは何か　学んだろう
right?
heaven time, the advantage of location, coordination of people.
天の時　地の利　人の和
そういうことだ
That's it.
And sindoor currently violates all three principles.
シンドゥラは今　その三つの理を全て犯している
殿下　夜も更けてまいりました
Prince, too late.
Maybe we break camp somewhere here?
この辺で　ひとまず陣を張るべきでは
いや　このまま山を越える
No, we continue to go through the mountains.
しかし　この寒さで　兵も馬もだいぶ体力を消耗しておりますぞ
But because of this cold and the people and the horses get tired.
だからこそ　立ち止まってしまうわけにはいかんのさ
That is why we can not just sit around.
山を越えればペシャワールの城はすぐそこだ
As soon cross the mountains, just go out to Peshavardu!
一気に…
And soon ...
A-attack!
敵襲
やはり来たか
Came the same!
Otherwise it would be boring.
そう来なくては面白くない
In the attack!
かかれ
まずは　三つの理の一つ　天の時
To begin with the first principle:
heaven time.
シンドゥラ兵は常夏の南国育ち
Soldiers sindoor grown in the south, where eternal summer.
真冬の雪山で果たしてどこまで戦えるかな
In the snow-covered mountains in winter
how well they can fight?
シンドゥラの蛮族ども　この双刀将軍キシュワードが相手になってやるぞ
Sindoor barbarians!
I Kisvard General two swords, your opponent!
Do not retreat!
ひるむな　シンドゥラの武勇　パルスの兵どもに見せつけてやれ
Show all soldiers Parsis valor sindoor!
Next area.
そして　地の利
来たか　ダリューン
Go, Daruna!
Attacked from both sides! Retreat!
挟み撃ちだ　退け
パルスは彼らにとって未知の土地　こちらは細かい地形まで把握済みだ
They do not know Parsa district.
And we are familiar with its topography.
So Daryun!
さあ　ダリューン
ヤシャスィーン
Jasasuiin!
押し返せ　それでもシンドゥラの男か
Pushes!
You people sindoor or anyone ?!
力任せに押し返そうとは…
They are trying to push the main force?
なんと傲岸な将だ
What an arrogant general!
甘かったな　俺の兵たちがこんな奇襲程度でひるむものかよ
Do not underestimate us!
My people will never yield to a surprise attack!
天の時　地の利を犯してまで攻め込んでくるだけの自信はあるということか
So he's confident enough in the invasion,
though time is against heaven and benefits area.
But what about the rest of coherence of people?
だが　残る人の和は　どうかな
このまま押せ
Continue to press!
Come from behind ?!
背後からだと
また新手か
Reinforcement?
いや　この音はシンドゥラの
No, it sounds sindoor ...
み…見ろ　あの旗印は…
C-look!
This banner ...
ガ…ガーデーヴィ殿下
P-Prince Gadevi!
なぜ　第一王子の軍が
え…援軍に来てくれたのでは
H-probably, come to our aid ...
ち…違う　ガーデーヴィ殿下は敵だ
N-no! Prince Gadevi our enemy!
大変です
We have problems.
What's that noise?
なんの騒ぎだ
According to the report, Prince Gadevi leads a huge army
ガーデーヴィ王子が大軍を引き連れ
我が軍の後尾に襲いかかってきた由にございます
and attack us from the rear!
Can not be!
バカな
俺がここにいることは　ガーデーヴィはまだ知らぬはず
Gadevi should know that I'm here.
あるいは　此度の我々の行動　全てひそかに監視されていたのでは
Or perhaps they secretly watched our every move.
It can not be!
まさか
You go around to the left!
左に回れ　背後からガーデーヴィの兵が迫ってきてるぞ
Gadevi people approaching from behind!
What are you doing? Left!
何をしている　左だ　前に出たら　パルス兵に殺されるぞ
If you leave ahead, you will be killed parsiantsy!
Though the night and moon,
新月の夜とはいえ
certainly, the soldiers are stupid,
通常なら　女　子供の声にだまされるような愚かな兵でもないだろうが
to distinguish the voices of women and children.
シンドゥラは現在　二人の王子による世継ぎ争いの真っただ中
But sindoor now!
a battle between the two princes of the right of inheritance.
意識せずとも　兵たちの心にも不安はあろう
Maybe they do not know,
but in the hearts of the soldiers hidden anxiety.
そこをつけば　崩れるのはあっという間だ
If they hit, they quickly break down.
これが人の和か
This coherence of people.
そろそろ　例の場所に近づきつつある
They are gradually approaching the spot.
頃合いだな
Good time.
さあ　５万と１万の戦力差　今ひっくり返してみせよう
Thus, the difference between fifty and ten thousand
It will now be refuted!
Yes!
なんだ　この音
What's that sound?
こ…これは　まさか
Uh, it's ...
Can not be!..
Come on! Get out of here! Here...
走れ　ここから離れろ　ここは…
そう　そこは凍った湖の上さ
Yes. This is the top of a frozen lake.
Am I still see a nightmare?
俺は悪夢でも見ているのか
ラジェンドラ王子に急ぎ申し上げたきことあり
I have an urgent message for Prince Rajendra!
殿下はおわすや
Prince here?
ラシェンドラはここにいる　何が起こった
Rajendra here! What happened?
Daryun, this is it.
ダリューン　この男だ
何
What?
悪いが　捕虜となっていただこう　ラジェンドラ王子
I'm afraid I'll have to take you prisoner, Prince Rajendra!
次に会ったら　生かしてはおかんぞ
In following our meeting I will not leave alive!
動くと死ぬよ　シンドゥラの色男
Dvineshsya, and you're dead, sinduriysky handsome.
いや　参った　参った
Yes, I caught, caught.
見事にしてやられたわ
Brilliantly outmaneuvered.
The Alfred, you are good to try.
アルフリード　よくやってくれた
いえ　ナルサス卿の策がよろしきを得たからにございます
What do you.
This is all thanks to the magnificent trick Mr. Narsusa.
聞いてはいたが　こんなにかわいい大将だったか
I heard, but did not know that their leader is so small.
So, what will you do with me?
で　俺をどうするつもりだ
見せしめに兵の前で処刑でもするかい
Penalty in front of my people, for the edification?
ラジェンドラ殿
Prince Rajendra I, Crown Prince Parsis, Arslan.
私はパルスの王太子　アルスラーンと申します
We treated a little roughly,
いささか乱暴でしたが　お話ししたいことがあって
but I would like to discuss with you
your appearance here.
このようにご招待いたしました
ほう　驚いたな
Such a surprise.
パルスでは　縄で縛って引っ立てることを招待と言うのか
The Pars binding and transport of person called an invitation?
For this I apologize.
これは　大変失礼しました
I would like to talk to you on equal terms.
これで対等にお話しできるかと思いますが
まあ　いいだろう
OK then.
聞いてやらんこともない
I did not say that it is not heard.
辺境の地ゆえ　大したおもてなしもできませんが
on the border
not much you can regale guests, but ...
I'll drink.
頂こう
おお　いやいや　この酒はなかなかいけるぞ
No no. This wine is pretty good.
シンドゥラにはない味わいだ
Such taste sindoor not.
さあ　皆も大いに食べ　飲んでくれ
So, we also have a drink to the dregs.
それにしても　まだ子供と聞いていたが　先刻は見事な采配だった
But still,
though I have heard that you are still a child,
but your command was terrific.
I am amazed Prince Arslan.
感服したぞ　アルスラーン王子
いえ　私は何もしておりませぬよ
No. I did not do anything.
仲間たちに助けられてばかりです
I only come to the rescue comrades.
Not subordinates and comrades?
臣下ではなく　仲間か　つくづく面白い男だな
You are a very interesting person.
Come on, come on! And you drink!
さあさあ　お主も　飲め飲め
あっ…　はい
Good.
I keep you company.
あなたのお相手は私がしよう
Oh, it's fine.
おお　それはいい
おっと　俺も交ぜてもらおうか
Oh well. Allow me to join.
酒の肴に楽士の詩はどうだい　王子様
What about the music of the singer to the wine, the prince?
Interesting. Then, make a little competition?
面白い　ならば　飲み比べといこうじゃないか
ああっ　いや…　あぁ…
No...
本当に二人ともよくやってくれた
You are a very good job.
ありがとうございます
Many thanks.
まあ　あの程度の任務　私一人で十分だったんだけどね
Well, such a mission ...
I would and she coped.
お前こそ引っ込んでてもらって結構だったさ　出しゃばり女
Just can cope without you, obsessive woman.
なっ…　出しゃばりって何よ　あんたの方がよっぽど出しゃばりじゃない
What do you mean an obsession?
You yourself everywhere thrusting his nose!
私はナルサスと話してるんだから
I'm talking to Narsusom!
You can even now get along a little bit, guys?
こんなときぐらい　仲よくできないのか　お前たち
Heck...
ちくしょう　頭の中で水牛の群れが合唱しながら踊ってやがるぅ
In my head I am singing in unison and even dancing herd unruly oxen.
With such secretly get drunk.
この俺が酔い潰せぬとは　侮れんなぁ　パルスの女
Women Parsis directly from steel.
Oh, I'm sorry.
おお　失礼した　さあ　もう一杯
So, for another.
And, well, uh ...
あっ　あっ　いや…
ラジェンドラ殿
Prince Rajendra.
Y-yes, Prince Arslan, how can I help?
アルスラーン王子　なんですかな
Let's continue our conversation.
先ほどの話の続きを
おうおう　もちろんです
Ah, yes! Of course!
話…　そういえば　なんの話だったか
Conversation...
By the way, what we talked about?
あなたと同盟を結びたい
I want to join with you in a union.
ABOUT...
ほう
聞こうか
Listen.
First, we will help you ascend to the throne sindoor.
まず
我々は
あなたがシンドゥラの王位につけるよう
お手伝いしてさしあげましょう
そのかわり　お主の戦にも力を貸せと
And in return you want me to help you in your war?
Yes.
ええ
悪い話ではないと思いますが
I think the deal is pretty good.
I would say, it's interesting.
面白いことを言う
国を追われた王子に何ができるというのだ
What a prince, banished from his own kingdom?
なんだと…
What?
Still, the prince Rajendra, you do not want to say so,
ですが　ラジェンドラ殿
こういってはなんですが　今の御身のお立場をよく考えていただきたい
I would like you to think about your current situation.
脅迫のつもりか
That is a threat?
俺の身に何かあってみろ　俺の兵たちは決して貴様らを許しはしないぞ
I try to do something.
My people so that you will not leave.
そんな野蛮なことはいたしません
I will not resort to such measures.
Yes.
ええ　というか　すでにシンドゥラ国内には通達してしまいました
Or rather, we have alerted people in sindoor.
About what?
何を
Prince and Crown Prince Rajendra Parsa, Arslan,
ラシェンドラ王子はパルス国のアルスラーン王太子との間に
友誼と正義に基づく盟約を結んだ…とね
We created a union based on friendship and honesty.
Wh-what ?!
なっ　なんだと
And the prince,
更に　王子はシンドゥラ国に平和をもたらすため
which will bring peace to the kingdom sindoor,
国都ウライユールへ進撃を開始した…とも
already moved into the royal Uraiyur capital.
貴様ら　俺を反逆者に仕立て上げようというのか
Oh, you! ..
Do you want to make me a traitor?
もとより　いずれ第一王子ガーデーヴィとは雌雄を決するおつもりだったのでしょう
You from the beginning is conceived
to fight Gadevi, the first prince, right?
それが少し早まっただけのことですよ
It just happens a little earlier.
私はあなたをガーデーヴィ王子との交渉に使いたくはない
I do not want to use you in negotiations with Prince Gadevi.
You have caught me, Crown Prince of Parsis.
やってくれたな　パルスの王太子よ
協力していただけますか
I count on the cooperation?
いいだろう
Okay.
このラジェンドラがお主に力を貸してやる
I, Rajendra, support you.
Fate Arslan turned in an unexpected direction.
アルスラーンの運命は再び思わぬ方向へと回りはじめた
The era of Parsis, December 320 years.
パルス暦３２０年１２月
アルスラーンはマルズバーン・キシュワードにペシャワール城塞の守護を任せ
Ostaviv oʙoronu kreposti Peşavarda Marzʙanu Kisvardu,
ラジェンドラ軍と共にシンドゥラを目指して　出陣を決めた
Arslan went to accompany the army Rajendra
in sindoor.
彼がいざなう先に何が待つのか　幼き王子はまだ知る由もない
What awaited them at the end of this road?
The young prince did not know it.
どうだ　アルスラーン殿　俺の自慢の兵たちは
What do you think, Prince Arslan, about my people, I'm proud?
I hope we will be friends.
よろしく頼むぞ
あの男　本当に信用していいものか
This guy...
We can definitely trust him?
YakuSub Studio
kimi ga deatta kokoro wa kitto
All the souls that you could meet on the way,
translation Mu_Cool
hitotsu datte machigai janai
certainly it was pure and innocent,
Editorial Mu_Cool
onaji yume wo daite
We kept the same dream.
Making Helge
michi wo tagaeta hito wo omotta
People walking different paths,
nozarashi no akogare wo kakagete susumu kouya
killed all my hopes and desires revive again.
hohoemi mo sono namida mo
Smile on his face, tears running down her cheeks,
koko ni suteteyukenai kara
If you want to go ahead, they should not be forgotten.
kage wo daite shiroku takaku
Covered by the shadow of the summer, so white and immense,
namonaki boku to kimi no hata
our with you nameless flag flies.
mada hatenaku tsudzuku kono mich ino kanata ni
There, on the road, which extends an endless path,
tatta hitotsu no hikari wo sen no kokoro ni
There is one bright light, and with it a thousand souls.
miageru sora wo shinjiteru
Believe in the sky above his head,
michibiku hoshi wo higashi no takami ni sashishimesu yo
there putevodnaâ our star in the east, ee do not engage.
yume wa kono te de kanaeru
And their cherished dream in flesh forces.
Royal capital Uraiyur Kingdom sindoor
愚かな弟だとは思っていたが
I thought the younger brother a fool, but ...
Crown Prince vermilion, Gdevi
But at the Pars ?!
まさか　パルスと…　アルスラーンなどという小僧と手を組むとは
Even with such a kid as Arlsan!
It seems that no matter what happens,
どうあっても　殿下の王位継承を認めるつもりはないということでしょうな
he is not going to recognize you heir to the throne.
Hereditary Grand Vizier kingdom sindoor, MS
いかがいたしましょう
What do we do?
Is not it obvious ?!
決まっておろう　ラジェンドラめを討つ
Rajendra destroy it!
そもそもヤツがおとなしく私の王位継承を認めれば　何も波乱は起きなかったのだ
If he had recognized my right to inheritance,
none of this would have happened!
承知いたしました
How view.
ご安心召されよ　ガーデーヴィ殿下
Be calm, Prince Gadevi.
すでにラジェンドラのもとには　私の配下の者を潜ませております
I have already introduced their own man to Rajendra.
ジャスワントの黒々とした両目には　緊張と失意が
The jet-black eyes Jaswant was seen tension and frustration.
ギーヴの紺色の両目には　不敵な笑いがあった
In deep eyes Gieva read as a fearless laugh.
次回　シンドゥラの黒豹
Next time: "Black Leopard sindoor."
Chapter XV
少年は　そして王となる
And so the guy would be King.
Art: Massimo Hiro